[
    {
        "question": "Which U.S. state features the Italian phrase `Fatti maschii, parole femine` as its state motto?",
        "answer": "Maryland (The motto translates as \u201cManly deeds, womanly words.\u201d  The state uses `Strong deeds, gentle words`.)"
    },
    {
        "question": "After a write-in contest, what did Alaska select as its motto?",
        "answer": "Juneau journalist, Richard Peter, suggested `North to the Future,` which was selected as Alaska`s official state motto in 1967."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which U.S. state has the motto `Ad astra per aspera` meaning `to the stars through difficulties`?",
        "answer": "Kansas"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which U.S. state has `Salus Populi Suprema Lex Esto` as its state motto?",
        "answer": "Missouri (The phrase translates to `Let the welfare of the people be the supreme law`.)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the oldest state park in the United States?",
        "answer": "Although Yellowstone is America`s oldest national park, New York`s Niagara Falls State Park was the first state park."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the body of water that the Golden Gate Bridge transverses.",
        "answer": "John C. Fr\u00e9mont gave it the name `Chrysopylae` or `Golden Gate` on July 1, 1846. The strait is commonly called `Golden Gate`."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which English city was Alfred the Great`s capital city?",
        "answer": "Winchester"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Hunua Ranges is located where?",
        "answer": "New Zealand"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Maluku islands (informally known as the Spice Islands) belong to which country?",
        "answer": "Indonesia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What major city elected Sadiq Khan, its first mayor from an ethnic minority, in 2016?",
        "answer": "Greater London, England"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country`s flag features an eagle eating a snake?",
        "answer": "Mexico"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you order `murgh` from the menu at an Indian restaurant, what meat will you get?",
        "answer": "Chicken"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the biggest country without a river?",
        "answer": "Saudi Arabia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What U.S. city is home to the historic Georgetown district?",
        "answer": "Washington D.C"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country was formerly called Zaire?",
        "answer": "The Democratic Republic of the Congo"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country is nicknamed the Land of 1,000 Lakes?",
        "answer": "Finland"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country has the longest town name?",
        "answer": "New Zealand"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which two countries are on the southern border of Mexico?",
        "answer": "Guatemala and Belize"
    },
    {
        "question": "What US state includes the telephone area code 515?",
        "answer": "Iowa"
    },
    {
        "question": "What US state includes the telephone area code 602?",
        "answer": "Arizona"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where`s the famed Arch of Hadrian?",
        "answer": "Athens"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city is the Arch of Hadrian located in?",
        "answer": "Athens"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country is the Arch of Hardian located in?",
        "answer": "Greece"
    },
    {
        "question": "What European country is the Arch of Hadrian located in?",
        "answer": "Greece"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Turkey?",
        "answer": "Ankara"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was Malawi formerly known as?",
        "answer": "Nyasaland"
    },
    {
        "question": "Lilongwe is the capital of which African country?",
        "answer": "Malawi"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is California also known as?",
        "answer": "The Golden State"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ocean does Tanzania have water access to?",
        "answer": "Indian"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of the US state Wisconsin?",
        "answer": "Madison"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Kyrgyzstan?",
        "answer": "Bishkek"
    },
    {
        "question": "Bishkek is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Kyrgystan"
    },
    {
        "question": "What continent is Kyrgystan located in?",
        "answer": "Asia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country borders Kyrgystan to the north?",
        "answer": "Kazakhstan"
    },
    {
        "question": "Lincoln is the capital of which state?",
        "answer": "Nebraska"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the `Natural State`?",
        "answer": "Arkansas"
    },
    {
        "question": "Rocky Mountain National Park is located in which state?",
        "answer": "Colorado"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is home to Arches National Park?",
        "answer": "Utah"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Napa Valley is located in which US state?",
        "answer": "California"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the Napa Valley best known for?",
        "answer": "Wine"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the largest city in the contiguous United States in terms of area?",
        "answer": "Jacksonville, Florida"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where did the Stonewall Riots take place?",
        "answer": "New York City"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the three official languages of Luxembourg?",
        "answer": "French, German, and Luxembourgish"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the tallest building in South America?",
        "answer": "Gran Torre Santiago, Santiago, Chile"
    },
    {
        "question": "When was Hong Kong transferred from Britain to China?",
        "answer": "1997"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the Philippines named after?",
        "answer": "Spain`s King Philip II"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the only US state with a Spanish motto?",
        "answer": "Montana"
    },
    {
        "question": "What city`s name means `Lion City`?",
        "answer": "Singapore"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country has a free wine fountain that`s open to the public?",
        "answer": "Italy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the only `road` in London, England?",
        "answer": "Goswell Road"
    }
]